M*A*S*H Gives A D*A*M*N.
M*A*S*H is a comedy, drama, war film directed by Robert Altman.
The staff of a Korean War field hospital use humor and hijinks to
keep their sanity in the face of the horror of war.
Hawkeye Pierce, played by Donald Sutherland.
Trapper John McIntyre, played by Elliott Gould.
Duke Forrest, played by Tom Skerritt.
Maj. Margaret 'Hot Lips' O'Houlihan, played by Sally Kellerman.
Maj. Frank Burns, played by Robert Duvall.
Lt. Col. Henry Blake, played by Roger Bowen.
Marrakesh or Marrakech (; Arabic: مراكش, romanized: murrākuš,
pronounced [murraːkuʃ]) is the fourth-largest city in Morocco.
It is one of the four imperial cities of Morocco and is
the capital of the Marrakesh-Safi region.
The city lies west of the foothills of the Atlas Mountains.
The city was founded circa 1070 by Abu Bakr ibn Umar as
the capital of the Almoravid dynasty.
The Almoravids established the first major structures in the
city and shaped its layout for centuries to come.
The red walls of the city, built by Ali ibn Yusuf in 1122–1123, and various buildings constructed in red
sandstone afterwards, have given the city the nickname of the "Red City" or "Ochre City".
Marrakesh grew rapidly and established itself as a cultural,
religious, and trading centre for the Maghreb.
After a period of decline, Marrakesh regained its status in the early 16th century as the capital of the Saadian dynasty,
with sultans Abdallah al-Ghalib and Ahmad al-Mansur embellishing the city with an array of sumptuous monuments.
Beginning in the 17th century, the city became popular among Sufi
pilgrims for its seven patron saints who are buried here.
In 1912, the French Protectorate in Morocco was established and T'hami El Glaoui became Pasha of Marrakesh and generally
held this position until the independence of Morocco and the reestablishment of the monarchy in 1956.
Marrakesh comprises an old fortified city packed with vendors and their stalls.
This medina quarter is a UNESCO World Heritage Site and contains the Jemaa el-Fnaa square, a large
number of souks (markets), the Kutubiyya Mosque, and many other historic and cultural sites.
The city serves as a major economic centre and tourist destination.
Property and hotel development in Marrakesh have
grown dramatically in the 21st century.
Marrakesh is particularly popular with the French, and numerous
French celebrities own property in the city.
Marrakesh is served by Marrakesh Menara Airport and by Marrakesh railway
station, which connects the city to Casablanca and northern Morocco.
Marrakesh has several universities and schools, including Cadi Ayyad University.
A number of Moroccan football clubs are based here, including Najm de Marrakech, KAC
Marrakech, Mouloudia de Marrakech and Chez Ali Club de Marrakech.
The Marrakesh Street Circuit hosts the World Touring Car
Championship, Auto GP and FIA Formula Two Championship races.
The film explores themes of american football, dark comedy,
surgeon, american  way of life, korean war (1950-53).
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.